What would you say
那你觉得
my weak spot is
我现在想成为一个
when it comes to
好的投资人
being a good investor?
短板是什么
You weak spot
你的短板
is...
就是
not having one.
没有短板
Stop kidding me.
你别开玩笑了
Your instinct for investment is spot on,
你的投资直觉很准
and you're investing in areas
而且现在又在
that you're familiar with,
你比较擅长的领域
categories like baby care.
比如母婴这些类目
You're able to make
你可以做出
comprehensive and accurate judgements.
全面准确地判断
But to go from here,
但是往上走呢
you need to step into
就需要你站在一个
a broader track of investments,
更加广阔的投资赛道上
involve yourself in all kinds of projects,
大量地接触项目
and broaden your horizon.
开阔视野
Seems like I have a lot to catch up on.
看来我急需补课了
Mr. Zhou,
周老师
if there're more occasions like this,
以后有这样的机会
please bring me along with you.
多带我出来见见世面
No problem.
没问题
I have a couple more things
那周老师
to tell you, Wendy.
就要多说两句温蒂同学
Aside from broadening your horizon,
既要开阔视野
you need to find your strength.
还要找到自己的优势
Give your best shot
在自己最擅长的领域
at what you're best at.
和方向去集中发力
One more thing,
而且
don't be afraid of making mistakes.
不要怕犯错
Have the courage to test things out.
要敢于试错
Sometimes what you learn from mistakes
有时候这个教训
become valuable experience.
是宝贵的经验
Whatever goes wrong,
出任何问题
you have me behind you.
有我担着
Keep in mind,
记住
behind every successful woman,
每一个成功的女人背后
there is a man.
都站着一个男人
And the man you have behind you
你的背后站的就是
is me.
我
Cut the jokes.
少贫了
That's the beat I want.
感受到我的点了 对吧
This is it.
就要这个
They are doing an excellent job.
他们家做得好
We'll work with them next time.
下次还找这个团队
Good job.
可以
No problem.
没问题
[Good job.]
加鸡腿哦
[But]
但是
[30 seconds?]
三十秒啊
[Who can keep]
谁能保持
[the vibe going for 30 seconds?]
热烈的气氛三十秒
[No,]
不行
[10 seconds at most.]
顶多十秒
[In 10 seconds, we'll have them]
十秒内就让他们
[completely warmed up and excited.]
烧起来 烧起来 烧起来
[So we have to pack]
所以我们要把
[the best parts]
所有精彩的部分
[into the first 10 seconds,]
全部挤进前十秒
okay?
好不好
No problem.
没问题
How does it feel to just sit back?
躺平的滋味好受吗
Honestly?
说实话吗
Yeah.
必须呀
It's pretty nice.
就还挺舒服的
You're living in your own world.
你是不是自洽过头了
What do you want me to do then?
那你让我干吗呀
You're the director.
你是总监
Do your job.
该干吗干吗呀
You can't be too optimistic.
这心不能太大
What if something goes wrong?
万一出事呢
It shouldn't.
应该不会
I wanted to start
这个项目
this project half a year ago.
我半年前就想做了
The perspective is very original.
视角很新颖
It doesn't involve any sensitive contents.
内容也在安全范围之内
Even if you have Mu work on it,
你就算交给阿木做
it can't go wrong.
也是稳赢的
Not to mention her.
何况是她呢
When this project gets going,
这个项目运营起来
it'll, at least, last half a year.
怎么也能撑个半年
In half a year,
半年之后
my kid will be born.
我孩子都生完了
That will be a smooth transition.
也算平稳过渡了
They say pregnancy leaves a woman dumb.
都说一孕傻三年
Is it true?
是不是真的
You're calling me dumb.
你说我傻
I'm not saying you're dumb.
我不是说你傻
I'm saying you can't just sit back.
我是说你不能大撒把
Regarding the strategy,
这个策略呀
talking is not enough.
不能只是靠嘴上说说
We have to carry it out.
还是要执行的
Did you forget
你是不是忘了咱俩
about our plan?
怎么设计的了
They're already on it.
人家现在都已经
It's already in action.
抡开膀子干了
They're already brought into the company.
人都带进公司了
If I don't sit back now,
我这时候不躺平
when would I?
什么时候躺平啊
We had a deal that I could rest
不是说好了上你这儿来
for the baby here.
安胎的吗
You become scheming.
你腹黑了
It's called wisdom.
我这叫智慧
Haowen.
浩文
Lin.
姐夫啊
What's up?
怎么了
How did Little Watermelon's
小西瓜这耳朵检测
hearing test go?
怎么样了
Don't panic.
你不慌啊
Calm down.
不慌 不慌
Haowen, there's got to be a way.
浩文 一定有办法
Sometimes the test... There...
有时候这检测 它会
must've been some mistakes.
它 中间它肯定有误会
We'll go to a different hospital.
我们再找一个医院
We'll take the test again.
我们再测一次
Maybe...
也许
No, I think it'll definitely...
不是也许 我觉得肯定
Lin,
姐夫
can't you wish us something good?
你能盼我们家点好行吗
Even though Little Watermelon
我们小西瓜
failed both tests,
虽然两次检测没通过
we're doing great.
我们现在可好了
In addition,
我再跟你说
my wife
我媳妇
has left the maternity hotel now.
也出了月子中心了
We also got
我们家还找了个
an amazing nanny.
特别好的月嫂
Everything's great
全是开心
Her hearing is fine?
耳朵没事了
Of course.
当然
It's normal?
正常了
Congratulations. This is awesome
祝贺 祝贺 太棒了
Haowen,
浩文
those days are finally over for you,
你算是熬出头了
right?
是不是
How about this?
这样
Haowen,
那个老贾
it's too late today,
今天来不及了
but some other day,
改日
I'll take you to a great place to eat.
我找个好馆子我请你
No need for the courtesies between us.
你跟我瞎客气什么
I come here for this,
我今天来是这个啊
from Xin to her sister.
心心给她姐拿的
She had it when she was pregnant,
她怀孕时候吃的
the supplements.
补品
She said it'll be great for her,
她说对大姐身体特别好
for her pregnancy.
为了安胎
So here it is.
给大姐送来
The good news
你来告诉我好消息
would've been enough.
就行了嘛
There's no need to bring gifts.
你还送礼给我
Well, it's not for you.
谁给你送了 你想得多
You're not pregnant.
你又不安胎
It's for Meng'an.
给姐的
Okay,
行 行
thank you then.
那我就收下了啊
Okay.
好
Lin, let me tell you,
姐夫 我跟你说啊
Meng'an's pregnancy is stable now.
姐现在也安胎了
It's a relief.
也踏实了
You'll soon have a new kid, too.
你们家马上也添丁进口
You'll be just as happy as I am.
你会跟我一样开心
But I'm telling you,
但是我告诉你
you must be as cautious as I am.
你一定要像我一样注意
I'm very cautious.
我 特别注意
I always keep your words in mind
我时刻拿你的话
as the truth.
当真理啊
"If there's a will, there's a way."
有志者 事竟成
Nope.
不对
"Pretending to be timid keeps you safe."
装   保平安
What else then?
那还有什么
Work hard and bear hardships.
吃苦耐劳
That's no news.
那不用准备
I'm like
我这个人啊 就是
the hardest working man
就是吃苦耐劳
himself.
本劳
We are the same,
咱俩连襟真是一样
Lin.
我的姐夫
I'll leave you to it then.
那你忙 我走了
Alright,
行
I'll get back to it.
那我忙去了啊
It's been so hard for you...
太不容易
Don't forget the gifts.
东西别忘了啊
Okay, I got it.
行行行 我收了 收了
Bye, Lin.
我走了 姐夫
Alright.
好嘞
Okay.
好
Keep up the good work.
你辛苦啊
Hang in there.
你辛苦 你辛苦
Work hard and bear hardships.
吃苦耐劳
You've had such a hard time
你太辛苦了
for the past months
这几个月的
It must've been overwhelming.
把你忙得兵荒马乱的啊
Our company focuses on
咱们公司主要是做
diagnostic equipment,
诊断设备
chemotherapy equipment,
化疗设备
and relevant training.
和培训
We hope we have
那希望周总
the chance
以后有机会
to see you often, Mr. Zhou.
常来我们公司坐坐
Sure.
好的
Thank you.
谢谢
Mr. Zhou.
周总
Mr. Yu.
于总
Are you available now?
那个 您有时间吗
I'd like to talk about my project.
我想跟您谈谈我的项目
We have to confirm it
下午咱们不就要
in the meeting this afternoon.
开会定了吗
Sure, let's talk over there.
好 我们那边聊吧
[The two project proposals I gave you,]
给你们的两个项目书
[you can start working on]
你们可以做下
[gathering the basic information.]
基础的摸底工作
[Pay special attention to their]
尤其关注一下他们
[funding source in the past two rounds.]
前两轮的融资来源
Okay, have it ready for me next Monday.
好 下周一给我吧
Mr. Yu, let me introduce.
于总 我来介绍一下
[Mr. Zhou.]
周总
This is our
这位是我们公司
Senior Investment Manager, Wendy.
高级投资经理 温蒂
Wendy,
温蒂
this is Mr. Yu from Blue Ocean Media.
这位是蓝海传媒的于总
You know each other well.
你们是老熟人了
Hello, Mr. Yu.
于总 你好
You work for
你现在
Mr. Zhou now?
在周总手下工作了
Wendy is our
温蒂是我们公司
best investor,
最优秀的投资人
as well as
未来也将是
a future partner of Yaohui.
耀辉的合伙人
Blue Ocean Media
蓝海传媒呢
has been working with us for a long time.
和耀辉接触了很久
Wendy,
温蒂
I think you are the best choice
我觉得这个项目
for this project
非你莫属
Mr. Zhou, I think
周总 我
it's better for me to withdraw.
还是回避一下吧
No,
不不不
no one knows Mr. Yu
没有人比你更了解
and Blue Ocean Media better than you.
于总和蓝海传媒
I trust you,
我相信
as a professional investor,
作为一个职业投资人
you won't be
你不会被
affected by your personal emotion.
个人情感所左右
I'm sure
一定会
you'll make the right
不带任何偏见地做出
and unbiased judgement.
合理的判断
This is our project proposal,
这是我们的计划书
Wendy.
温蒂总
I know about this project.
这个项目我知道
Mr. Yu,
于总
I heard that your company just lost
听说你们蓝海前段时间
your content director
内容总监
and the core team.
和核心团队走了
Does it have any effects on you?
对你们蓝海有影响吗
We are the biggest
我们蓝海在咱们春江市
media company
是最大的
in Chunjiang City.
新媒体传媒公司
Slight alteration in personnel
这点小的这个人事变动
won't affect our business.
不会影响到我们的业务
I still need to
那我还是需要
look into that.
深入调研一下
I hope to have your cooperation.
希望你配合
You see,
你看
I said you are the best choice,
我说你是最合适的人选
you know about it more than anyone.
你最了解情况
That's why
所以这个项目
this project belongs to you.
非你莫属
That's it then.
那就这么定了
I'll leave Blue Ocean to you.
蓝海交给你了
Sure.
行
Since Mr. Zhou said the word,
周总发话了
I won't refuse.
那我就不推辞了
Okay, that's it for business.
好 公事谈完了
Since we all know each other well,
大家既然都认识
we can get together
以后我们可以
once in a while.
经常聚一聚
Mr. Yu, do you play golf?
于总 你打高尔夫吗
If you do,
要打的话
let's practice together next week.
咱们下周一起练练球
Sure, I do have a set of clubs.
行 我倒是有一套杆
Then I'll follow your schedule.
那我随时听您招呼
Great.
太好了
Wendy, please arrange a time for us
温蒂你安排一下
next week.
下周约个时间
Let's go together,
咱们一起去
play some golf and chat about business.
边打球 边谈谈项目
Okay.
行
Mrs. Li, you're so lucky.
云阶妈妈 你真幸福
Are you almost due?
这是快生了吧
In a few more months.
还得几个月呢
I'm so jealous.
真羡慕你啊
At my age,
我这个年龄啊
there's no chance.
想都不敢想
Why not?
这有什么不敢想的啊
Have one if you can.
能生就生呗
[My kid]
你看我们家那个
[is so easy to bring up.]
怎么养都能活
Easier said than done.
你说得倒是容易
I'm unable to do what I hope to do.
心有余而力不足
[My hands are full]
我就光忙活这一个呀
[with just one kid.]
就够我受的了
[Don't overthink it.]
别考虑那么多了
[It's not that much work.]
有什么好忙活的
[Keep working on it.]
再努力
[Have another one.]
继续生
Here they come.
出来了
It's mock exam today.
今天模拟考试
Yeah.
是 是 是
I wonder how it goes.
也不知道考得怎么样啊
It seems like it goes well.
这一看考得不错呀
Here's Wang Zhe.
王哲来了
Wang Zhe,
王哲
here.
这儿
How was your exam?
考得怎么样啊
What do you think?
你觉得呢
That's my son.
我儿子错不了
Excuse us.
我们先走了啊 先走了
Mr. and Mrs. Li,
叔叔 阿姨
Yunjie has to stay after school.
云阶被留校了
[Stay after school?]
留校了
[What happened, Lu?]
这怎么回事啊 璐璐
[After she eats,]
你这吃饱了
[put her on her left side,]
就让她往左侧睡
[or she might vomit.]
要不然容易吐奶
[Right.]
对对对
[Yeah, but the baby can't]
对 这 但是宝宝也不能
[just sleep on one side all the time.]
老朝一个方向睡啊
[The shape of her head]
那头型
[might be abnormal, right?]
是吧 就容易睡偏了
[Right.]
对
[The head shape]
现在大家都可在意
[is a big deal now.]
孩子这头型了
Yeah.
就是 就是
Yeah, we just wanted
是的 我们以前就是
her head to look nice.
那个头 睡得漂亮一点
Yeah.
对对对
But,
那
but the baby can turn over herself.
那宝宝自己不会转头啊
Just adjust her position
您就隔一段时间
once in a while.
给她再调整调整
Turn her over.
翻翻 翻翻身哈
Let me note it down.
我记一下
Yes, the left side.
对 是左侧
Left side.
左侧
Looking after babies these days
现在养孩子跟过去
are completely different from the past.
可是大不一样了
Yeah.
是
I have to write down what you said.
你说这些我都得记下来
Yeah, write them down.
对对对 记下来
[Your baby]
这宝宝
[is so lucky to have]
有您这么上心的奶奶
[such a loving grandmother.]
可真是太幸福了
Now that we have you,
你说你这一来呀
I get nothing to worry about.
我啥心都不用操了
You're doing all the work.
那活都让你干了
I have to learn from you
我得跟你好好地学学
the scientific and modern nursing.
你现代的 科学的育儿
Shanshan, teach me too.
珊珊 你也教教我
Mrs. Jia,
阿姨
maybe one day
说不准以后
I'll be working as a nanny.
我也出去挣钱去了
Ask me whatever you want.
你们有啥不懂的就问我
Okay.
行
Um...
那个
inform shareholders about meeting tomorrow
通知股东明天开会啊
and send me the revised blueprint.
把修改蓝图发给我
I'll have a look tonight.
晚上我看一下
Alright.
好
[Okay.]
好的 好的
[Shanshan,]
珊珊啊
[what you said...]
看你说这些啊
[Daddy's back.]
爸爸回来喽
[My baby.]
宝宝呀
[Daddy loves you.]
爱你呦
Was she behaving well today?
她今天乖不乖啊
She was so good.
可乖了
She ate well and slept well,
吃好睡得好
such an angel.
天使宝宝
[Yeah.]
对呀
[Shanshan did such a great job.]
也还是珊珊带得好
She's got so much experience.
带孩子真有经验哪
After we got Shanshan with us,
你看 珊珊来了以后
the baby hasn't puked once.
这孩子一次都没吐过
[Professionals]
这专业的
[are different after all.]
到底是不一样啊
Shanshan, thank you.
珊珊 谢谢你啊
You did such a great job.
孩子带得真好
[It's such a relief for me]
你来我们家呀
[that you're here.]
这个我都踏实了
[You are taking good care]
把这娘仨
[of the three ladies.]
照顾得都特别好
Yeah.
是是是
I don't have to worry at work,
我在外面工作都踏实
right, mom?
是吧 妈
That's right.
对 没错
My mom speaks highly of you every day,
我妈天天夸你
in every way possible.
三百六十度的
Thank you.
谢谢
Shanshan is so great.
珊珊真的好啊
[Yeah.]
对
[Now that we have her,]
她来了以后啊
[I have]
我真的那是
nothing to worry about.
啥事都不用管了
[She can cook]
不光会做饭
[and has so much energy.]
而且你看人也精神
[She's quick with her hands.]
看上去利利索索的
Most importantly, she's good to our kid.
关键是她对咱家孩子好
Have you seen her
你看她平时
holding Little Watermelon?
抱着小西瓜的样子
You can tell that
那是看得出
she really likes
她真心实意地
Little Watermelon.
喜欢咱家的小西瓜啊
Yeah.
就是 就是 就是
[Little Watermelon]
这说来说去啊
[is so lucky]
咱家小西瓜福气好
[Yeah.]
是
to have Shanshan,
能碰到珊珊
such a good nanny,
这么好的一个阿姨
right?
对不对啊
Lucky girl.
是 有福气
[She's laughing.]
笑了吧
It makes her happy.
高兴 高兴
Keep it down.
小点声
Don't scare her.
小点声 别吓着孩子啊
You're happy?
开心啊
Is she laughing?
笑了是吧
Yeah, she's laughing.
笑了 笑了
[She can recognize people now.]
认人了现在
[Yeah.]
就是
Are we eating or what?
还吃不吃饭了
[She's so happy.]
开心得不行
Time to eat!
吃饭了
Xin,
心
I come back just to eat with you.
我专门回来陪你吃饭的
[Come on, let's go eat.]
来来来 我们去吃
Ms. Xue,
薛老师
is there any
这里边是不是
misunderstandings.
有什么误会啊
I know my daughter.
我女儿我还是很了解的
These notes can not be hers.
这小抄肯定不是她的
Ms. Xue,
薛老师
even if my daughter fails a test,
我女儿就算是考不及格
she wouldn't do something like that.
她也不会做这样的事情
But we all watched
可是监控录像的
the whole security footage.
全程咱们都看了
The exam proctor
确实是监考老师
did find them in her desk.
从她的抽屉里面发现的
We've all the evidence.
这证据都在呢
Yes,
是
in the footage,
监控里是看见了
the exam proctor
监考老师
did find the notes
从云阶的抽屉里
in Yunjie's desk,
发现了小抄
but we didn't see
但是我们没有看见
Yunjie
云阶亲手把
putting the notes there herself,
这个小抄放进课桌吧
right?
对吧
Maybe it is her deskmate?
有没有可能是她同桌呢
It can't be. Her deskmate
那不可能
is the student leader of study.
她同桌是学习委员
Ms. Xue, that,
薛老师 这个话
I also disagree with.
我又不同意了
There's no guarantee that
学习委员
the student leader of study
和不可能作弊之间
definitely won't cheat.
没有必然的因果关系吧
I agree.
这个我同意的
I was the student leader of study,
我小时候也是学习委员
and I was so scared
越到考试的时候
when we had exams.
越害怕的
Yeah.
是啊
But Zhu Kexin's grades
但朱可欣的成绩
are top of the class.
是数一数二的
I put her next to Yunjie
我让她跟云阶同桌
in order to
就是为了
motivate Yunjie to study.
让她带动云阶学习的
Ms. Xue,
薛老师
you know,
您看
you asked to see us
您找我们来也是为了
so we can resolve this.
解决这件事情哈
Can we now
那我们现在
look closer into it?
就排查一下呗
Maybe it wasn't her deskmate.
有可能不是她同桌
Maybe those in front of or behind her?
是前后桌呢
Do you think you can
您看有没有可能
call their parents
您给这些家长
and ask them
都打个电话问一问
about the situation?
了解一下情况
There could be a chance.
万一呢
Yeah.
对
We need to look closer into it.
我们需要排查一下
We can't wrong
总不能冤枉一个
an innocent child.
无辜的好孩子吧
Okay, I'll make some calls.
好的 我打几个电话
What a big meal.
这么大一桌子菜
Mom,
妈
this is great.
真好啊
Xin,
心
mom made all these food
妈为了给你补身子
to help you recover.
你看这鸡鸭鱼肉的
Just eat more.
多吃啊
It's all thanks to you.
都沾了你的光了
Shanshan made all these.
这些都是珊珊做的
I can't cook them all.
我哪有这手艺啊
[Shanshan]
珊珊这人啊
[is so good at her job.]
干活实在太利索了
[She's not only good at babysitting.]
不仅仅孩子带得好
[You see,]
你看
[after the baby goes to sleep,]
孩子一睡觉
[she goes on]
她开始
[to do the laundry, cook, and clean up.]
洗衣服做饭搞卫生
[What a great meal she made,]
这一桌子菜做得好吧
much better than me.
比我做得强多了
I will ask Shanshan to be my teacher.
我准备拜珊珊为师呢
That's enough, mom.
行了吧 妈
Be your teacher.
您还拜她为师呢
Cooking takes talent.
做饭要凭天赋的
It's about a feeling.
做饭是感觉
You should just sit back and enjoy.
您就踏踏实实享清福
Okay.
好
What do you think, Xin?
你说呢 心
There's no taste at all.
一点咸味都没有
And it's greasy.
还那么油
It's terrible.
难喝死了
I'm done.
不喝了
Mom,
妈
there's really no salt in it?
真没放盐啊
She can't have any salt.
这不能放盐
If she has any...
这要放了盐
That's enough.
行了 行了 行了
Everything is about producing milk.
整不整就下奶
How can you have it without salt?
这不放盐怎么喝呀
Tastes like nothing.
白不呲咧的
You.
你这
Ying,
英子
bring the salt over.
把盐拿来
You're really...
真是
You've changed a lot.
你变化真大
I never change actually.
其实我一直没变
It's just
只是之前
you didn't notice before.
你不在意
Can you give me another chance?
能再给我次机会吗
Please talk about business.
请谈公事
Okay,
好
business.
谈公事
Mr. Zhou Yao
周耀周总呢
is a leading figure
他是投资界的
in the field of investment.
一个风向标
Blue Ocean
我们蓝海
wants to make our transition,
想实现自己的转型
and we need the support of Yaohui group.
需要耀辉集团的支持
It doesn't need to be a lot,
其实也不需要投很多钱
just to show
只要能表示出
that Yaohui group
耀辉集团
values
对我们蓝海的看重
and supports Blue Ocean.
和支持就可以了
Are you afraid
你不是怕
that I might trip you up?
我给你使绊子吧
Don't worry.
你放心
I'm now a professional investor.
我现在是职业投资人
I will not be biased.
咱们就事论事
I will look into your company
我会好好研究你们公司
and your projects.
和你的项目
Is there anything else?
还有事吗
If that's all,
如果没有别的事
please excuse me.
我先走了
Your mom and I both trust you.
我跟你妈都相信你
We know you didn't cheat.
没作弊就是没作弊
You're a good kid.
你是好孩子
Our daughter
咱们家云阶
never lies.
从来不说谎
What're you doing?
干吗呢
I'm trying to think of evidence.
我这 想证据呢嘛
You can't think of evidence.
证据是靠想的吗
You have to find it.
证据是靠找的
Right now, say something.
你现在你就 说两句
Yunjie...
云阶
Ms, Xue.
薛老师
I called
我打了电话
Zhu Kexin's mother.
给朱可欣的妈妈
Zhu Kexin admitted
朱可欣承认了
that the notes were hers.
那个小抄是她的
She heard that the proctor was coming,
她听说巡考的老师要来
so she tossed the notes
就把那个小抄
in Yunjie's drawer.
丢在云阶的抽屉里了
Zhu Kexin's mother
朱可欣妈妈
is on her way.
已经在路上了啊
She'll be here soon.
她马上就到了
I told you it wasn't me,
我就说我没作弊嘛
and you wouldn't believe me.
你还不信我
We believe you.
相信
Your dad and I always believe you.
爸妈一直都相信你
Ms. Xue
老师不是
helped you clear it out,
替你查清楚了吗
right?
是不是
It was our negligence.
也是我们疏忽了
It's fine.
没事 没事
Thank you, Ms. Xue.
谢谢薛老师啊
Mr. Li,
叔叔
Mrs. Li,
阿姨
Ms. Xue,
老师
I got some drinks
我买了点水
for you.
你们喝
This kid
这孩子
got us drinks.
给买水了
Okay, thank you.
好 谢谢啊
Mrs. Li, please.
云阶妈妈 您喝水
You, too.
您喝
Thank you.
谢谢啊
Goodbye Mr. and Mrs. Li.
叔叔阿姨再见
Goodbye Ms. Xue.
老师再见
Okay.
好
This is Mrs. Zhu.
这是可欣妈妈啊
Mrs. Li,
云阶妈妈
I'm so sorry.
对不起
Those notes,
那些小抄
Kexin admitted they were hers.
可欣她承认了 是她的
Ms. Xue said
我听薛老师说
Kexin's grades are not bad.
可欣学习成绩不错啊
Why would she...?
她怎么 还
She's afraid she can't surpass Wang Zhe,
她是怕 考不过王哲
so she went to the printing shop
所以她去复印店
and printed those out.
就印了那些
It's my fault, too.
其实这也怪我
I forced her.
是我逼她的
I forced her to get first in the exam.
我逼她非得考第一
She's under so much pressure,
这孩子压力太大了
so she...
所以她就
Li Yunjie,
李云阶同学
you have been wronged.
你受委屈了
It's my daughter's fault.
是我女儿不对
I apologize to you on her behalf.
我代表她 向你道歉
Mrs. Zhu, it's okay.
阿姨 不用不用
You didn't do anything wrong.
您没有做错
It was Zhu Kexin
错的是朱可欣
who made a bad mistake.
用了不正确的手段
It should be her
要道歉
apologizing to me.
应该她来给我道歉
She...
她
Mrs. Zhu,
可欣妈
maybe you should take them
你要不还是带着他们
to Kexin.
去找可欣吧
[Mr. Jia,]
贾总啊
[you're so good at it.]
您这手法很娴熟啊
[You know exactly what you're doing.]
一看就是带过孩子的
[No, I'm not.]
娴熟啥呀
[We weren't well off back then.]
那时候家里条件不好
[Xin just had the baby.]
心心生孩子辛苦
[As the dad, I've got to step up.]
我这当爹的 怎么办呀
[I burped him, fed him at night,]
晚上给他拍嗝 喂奶
[gave him bath.]
洗澡
[I had to do it all.]
全都得管着
[There was no other way.]
没办法
[It was difficult for the kid.]
孩子也不容易
[It was also difficult for Xin.]
心心也不容易
[She was going through so much.]
那么辛苦
[I couldn't let her do it.]
我哪儿舍得啊
You're such a good husband,
你可真是个好丈夫
a good father.
好爸爸
[Don't flatter me.]
啥好不好的
I was so busy in the daytime.
那会儿公司白天忙
I could only be with the baby at night.
晚上我就陪着宝宝
Because I love you.
因为我爱你呦
Really, the company
真的是公司
grew up with my child.
跟宝宝一起长大的
Here, let's
来 翻个
turn over.
翻过来
Take it slow.
慢点 慢点 慢点
Such a
像您这么
devoting father like you
亲力亲为的父亲
is hard to find these days.
现在可真是不多见了
The truth is,
其实我跟你讲
my conditions at first
我这人条件啊
weren't great.
刚开始真的不好
I was not
我也没那么大的
that ambitious, either.
远大志向
All I want
我就想着
is a happy family with my wife and kids.
老婆孩子热炕头
[I'll be home whenever I get the time.]
只要有空我就回家
[Right?]
是吗
Be home for you.
回来陪你
If everyone's like you,
要是都像您这样
I won't have a job.
那我可就失业了
Shanshan, that's not true.
珊珊 那真不一样 那
It's not the same thing.
那不叫失业
We all play different roles.
那分工不同
I'm jealous of your job.
我还羡慕你工作呢
You're the boss of such a big company,
您都这么大老板了
and you're still so busy?
这 这 还这么辛苦啊
What boss?
啥大老板
[Daddy is not a big boss.]
爸爸不是大老板啊
[Daddy works for the investors]
是给人投资人打工的
[to feed you.]
给你赚奶粉的
[Your job is great,]
你的工作好
[Shanshan.]
珊珊
[What a pleasant job to]
每天看这么漂亮的宝宝
[look after such a cute baby every day.]
心情多愉快呀
Why put me in charge
为什么让我负责蓝海
of the project with Blue Ocean?
这个项目
I find
我觉得
it's better for me to withdraw.
我还是避嫌比较好
You're not testing me, are you?
你不会是在试探我吧
To see if I'm loyal to the company?
看我对公司忠不忠诚
You've watched too much spy movies.
你谍战片看多了吧
There's no need for that.
没那个必要
I put real money
我可是真金白银
in it.
花出去的
Wendy,
温蒂
you're overthinking it.
你想多了
Why then?
那是为什么
I'm just curious.
我纯粹就是好奇
Seeing you two today,
我今天看到你俩的关系
I think it is pretty funny.
我觉得蛮好玩的
Don't you think
你不觉得
being around your ex-husband
你以现在的身份
as who you're today
去面对你的前夫
is quite satisfying?
很爽吗
Mr. Zhou, please don't put me in
周老板 以后这种局
any more of these occasions.
不要再安排了
I can't satisfy
我满足不了
your curiosity.
你这颗好奇的心
I was just joking.
开玩笑 开玩笑啊
Actually, I did it
其实我这么做
for a good reason.
是有正当理由的
I want you
我想让你自己呢
to test
去探索
your own limit.
你能力的边界
You know,
你看
you and Yu Hai have an unusual relation.
你跟于海的关系不一般
We can all understand that.
这个大家都能理解
But as investors,
但是我们作为投资人
we have to deal with
就是要会去处理
complicated relationships like that,
这种复杂的人际关系
to maintain,
要维系
clients,
客户
investors,
投资人
and startup companies,
还有创业公司
complicated relationships between them.
这种错综复杂的关系
And I think
而且我认为
women
女性
can deal with them better than men.
比男性更擅长处理关系
Really?
是吗
Don't you think so?
你不觉得吗
Don't you want to try?
你不想试试吗
Prodding me into action?
激将法
You have what it takes.
你身上有这个能力
Look,
你看
you've balanced your family,
你把家庭
career planning, vocational learning
事业规划 职业学习
so well.
平衡得很好
I hope, with this case,
我希望你能通过这次
through working with your ex-husband,
和你前夫的共事呢
you can manage
能够处理好这种
the most difficult relation like it.
最棘手的人际关系
I need someone like that
我需要一个这样的
as my career partner.
事业合作伙伴
I've given you a task.
现在周老师出题了
Here you go.
答题吧
But it seems to me
但是在我看来呢
that your divorce
你俩的离婚
was rather unpleasant.
似乎不太愉快
If you can learn
如果你能学习
to manage your relation,
处理好你俩的关系
I think
我觉得会对
it'll be good
两个孩子的
for your kids' growth
身心发展有帮助
and for your
也会对你未来的
future career development.
事业发展有帮助
It's true.
真的
You're right.
是的
Thank you, Mr. Zhou.
谢谢周老板
I know you're taking care of me.
我知道你替我着想
I'm also training you.
我也是为了锻炼你
You're welcome.
不客气
Don't you think the wine today
你不觉得今天的酒
has a peculiar taste?
有股味吗
Peat flavor.
泥煤味
No,
不是
it's a bit straight.
胡味
What?
糊味
Is it?
我怎么没有喝出来
Yeah, it's just like the straight face
就是那种一本正经地
when you are talking nonsense.
胡说八道的胡味
Kexin.
可欣
Let's go.
跟妈走
Why did you pull me away?
你刚刚拉我干吗呀
She didn't apologize yet.
我还没让她给我道歉呢
But
不是
you saw
你不是都看见了吗
how hard it is
那朱可欣
for Zhu Kexin and her mother.
和她妈多不容易啊
It is hard for them,
不容易归不容易
but is it easy for anyone these days?
现在谁容易呀
Dad
那我爸之前
was unemployed.
不还失业了吗
Still, our conditions
那我们家的家庭条件
are much better.
还是要好很多的
Didn't you hear her on our way there?
去的路上没听她妈说吗
She's a single mom right now.
她们现在是单亲家庭
So what?
单亲家庭怎么了
Your logic is flawed.
你这个逻辑就有问题
Being unfortunate doesn't excuse you.
不是谁弱谁就有理
Ever since you were pregnant,
我发现你自从怀孕之后
you've gotten a lot more unreasonable.
变得特别不讲道理了
Watch your language, Yunjie.
怎么说话呢 云阶
I'm not wrong.
本来就是嘛
I just want
我现在就想
her apology.
让她给我道个歉
Is that wrong?
我有错吗
Is that too much?
我过分吗
But I think
不过我觉得
Yunjie's got a point too.
云阶说得也有道理啊
Well then...
那
Am I wrong?
那我有错吗
My progesterone level is high right now.
我现在就是孕激素很高
I can't see them crying there,
就见不得母女当街落泪
okay?
怎么了
It was obvious
那很明显呀
that Zhu Kexin knew
朱可欣已经知道
that she made a mistake.
自己错了
What else do you want from her?
你们还想怎么样啊
Enough is enough.
杀人不过头点地呢
What do you want?
干什么呀这是
You're old enough
都多大人了
Can't you learn to be more forgiving?
不能学得宽容点吗
Am I wrong?
我说得不对吗
Honey,
老婆
I love you honey.
我爱你呦
You work so hard.
老婆太辛苦了
You've done the most
老婆为了这个家
for our family.
付出的最多了
You went through so much
老婆为了
to bring that kid
生我们家这个小崽子啊
into the world.
受大罪了
You had to have a C-section.
肚子上还挨了一刀
The cut
简直是这个刀
went into you,
落在了我老婆身上
but it hurt me, too.
痛在了我的心里
I should've charged in there
我当时真的应该冲进去
and taken it for you.
替我媳妇挨这么一刀
I felt so terrible, honey.
我心痛啊 老婆
I felt so terrible.
我太心痛
You've gone through so much, honey.
我老婆太辛苦了 老婆
My sweetheart.
我媳妇啊
Go away.
滚
Honey, how can I go?
老婆 我怎么能滚呢
Where can I go?
我滚哪儿去
I can only be next to you,
我只能滚在你的身边
by your feet,
滚在你的脚下
fall for your beauty,
滚在你的石榴裙下
honey.
老婆
There's no guarantee
你陪谁
who you'll be with.
还没个准呢
Honey,
老婆
that's really not true.
真不能这么说
Listen to me,
我跟你讲
every single moment,
我无时无刻心里
I'm thinking of you.
时时刻刻都想着你
I think of you when I drive,
我开车想着你
when I work,
工作想着你
when I eat.
吃饭的时候我都想着你
Honey,
老婆
I'm so lonely
没你的日子
without you.
我真的好孤单
Honey,
媳妇
I passed by
我今天路过了一个
a silk store today
丝绸店
and saw
看见一个
a gorgeous kerchief.
巨漂亮的这个丝巾
I took it out
我拿出来一看
and knew that this kerchief
这个丝巾啊
would look better
除了我媳妇
on my wife
全世界
than anyone else in the world.
谁戴上都没你漂亮
It's just a kerchief.
不就是一条丝巾吗
Stop it.
至于吗
Your gifts before I had the baby
生孩子前送什么呀
were much better than a kerchief.
生完了之后就送丝巾
The thought behind it really counts.
真是礼轻情意重啊
Honey,
媳妇
I've sinned.
我罪该万死
This is my fault.
我有罪
It's been
我们家孩子
so many days
都长这么大了
since our baby's birth.
都这么多天了
I didn't think of
我都没想起给老婆
a decent gift for you.
买个像样的礼物
I'm so sorry, honey.
我真的对不起老婆
This is completely
这完全是
my fault.
我贾浩文的错误
It's my fault.
贾浩文的问题
Let me make up
我赔不是
for my sins.
我赔罪
I have a magic trick to show you.
我给我媳妇变魔术
It'll definitely
一定能把我媳妇
make you laugh.
变开心了
Honey, look.
老婆 看
Look.
你看
I learned a magic trick, look.
我学会变魔术了 你看
Blow on it.
你吹一口
Do you like it?
漂亮吗
I love you.
我爱你啊
It'll look gorgeous on you.
你戴最好看了
Do you like it?
高兴了吧
Actually,
其实我现在
I don't want anything right now.
什么都不想要
I just want to be on my own,
我就想一个人
take some time off somewhere,
出去散散心
lie on the beach,
一个人去海边躺一躺
no more feeding at night,
没有夜奶
no more distress over the baby,
没有孩子的苦恼
no more being around the family.
没有一大家子
Easy.
容易
Got it.
明白
That's all?
我媳妇就这点要求啊
It's too easy.
这太简单了
When our child gets a bit older.
等咱家孩子再长大点
The four of us,
咱一家四口
we'll go to the beach.
去海边
We'll go see the blue ocean,
看着湛蓝的大海
feel the breeze,
吹着海风
watch sunrise over the sea.
看着海边的日出
We watch the beach,
看着沙滩
go surfing with the kids,
带着两个孩子冲浪
enjoy sunbath with my wife
带着我媳妇日光浴
and our nephew and niece,
还有姐姐的孩子
and our parents.
还有爸爸妈妈
What a happy family I have.
儿女双全
What
我贾浩文
did I, Jia Haowen, do
前世积了什么样的德
to deserve this?
我才有这样的福报
My sweetheart,
我亲爱的老婆
the ocean,
大海
the waves,
海浪
seabirds
海鸥
flying
飞翔
over the water.
浪花
So beautiful.
太美了
[Hold it yourself.]
自己拿
Daddy loves you.
宝宝爱你呦
Baby.
宝贝
Look.
看
Okay.
好了 好了 好了
Here, hold one yourself.
来 自己拿一个
Touch it.
摸一摸
She's a little upset.
有点不高兴了 这是
Baby.
宝贝
Jia Haowen!
贾浩文
I'm here.
来了
What's wrong, honey?
咋了 老婆
Where's Little Watermelon?
小西瓜呢
You scared me, honey.
吓死我了 老婆
She's with the nanny.
小西瓜让月嫂刚抱走了
How will I feed her at night?
那我晚上喂奶怎么办
It's fine, honey.
媳妇 你放心吧
There's still some breast milk
冰箱里不是还有你存的
in the fridge.
母乳吗
If it's not enough,
万一不够
Shanshan will give her some milk powder.
让珊珊再给她补点奶粉
But what if Shanshan
不是 那珊珊要是晚上
does something bad to her?
对小西瓜不好怎么办
Honey, don't worry.
老婆 你放心吧
There're cameras.
有监控呢
What's more,
再说
mom is with them.
还有奶奶盯着呢嘛
Don't worry.
放心吧
Honey,
老婆
I really think
我真的觉得
you need
你最近该睡一个
a good sleep.
囫囵觉了
Really
真的
It's been so hard on you.
老婆 你太辛苦了
You see,
你看平时
before we had Little Watermelon,
之前没有小西瓜的时候
as soon as there's
我老婆那脑门上
one single wrinkle on your forehead,
要有一个纹
you'll be going to the beauty salon.
马上就去美容院
You looked great.
可漂亮了
And now,
现在
you haven't been out for days,
整天整天不出门
never go downstairs,
一周一周不下楼
right?
是不是
Right?
是吗
Why would I go down?
下楼干吗啊
Who should I go out with?
出去给谁看呀
My hands are full with the baby.
我顾孩子还来不及呢
Jia Haowen,
贾浩文
you think I'm not pretty anymore?
你是不是嫌我丑了
Honey,
媳妇
I wouldn't dare.
我哪儿敢啊
honey, look,
老婆 你看啊
we have a nanny now,
咱家现在月嫂来了
right?
对吧
She's not bad.
这体验感也不错
Little Watermelon is healthy
小西瓜长得又结实
and strong.
又壮
So I think
那我觉着
you should take a break
你好好休息休息
and love yourself.
关心自己了
Honey,
老婆
have a good sleep tonight.
今天晚上睡个好觉
Don't worry about anything else.
别的事 什么都不想
When you wake up, don't worry about her.
明天醒了 不用带孩子
I have meetings the whole day tomorrow.
我明天开一天的会
I'll pick you up when I'm done.
开完会回来我就接你
It's been a while since our last date.
好久没约会了
I've made a reservation
我订好地儿了
for a candlelight dinner,
烛光晚餐
just the two of us.
就咱俩
Are you happy?
高兴吗
That's great.
这还差不多
Wendy,
温蒂总
Mr. Yu is waiting for you upstairs.
于总已经在楼上等您了
Mr. Yu.
于总
we're here.
我们来了
Let's get started.
可以开始了
I've been waiting
这一刻
for this moment for a long time.
我已经等了很久了
Please.
请
This is last week's
这是上周测试的
user analysis report.
用户分析报告
The user conversion rate is so high.
这用户转化率这么高
And most importantly,
重要的是
there are a lot of
新用户的注册量
registered and active new users.
和活跃度非常高
In fact,
事实上
the outsourcing team
经过外包团队
has had some great results
最近的搭建
through their work
和小规模测试
and recent small-scale tests.
效果非常好
Okay.
好好好
That is to say
这么说来
this team is good.
这个外包团队很厉害嘛
Ms. Huang,
黄副总监
you have a great team.
你的特种部队啊
That's it from me.
我汇报完了
Ms. Xu,
许总监
do you have anything to add?
您还有什么要补充的吗
No.
没有
That's it then.
那 那就散会吧
Ms. Huang,
黄副总监
can you send me a copy
能不能把你的汇总报告
of your summary report?
发我一份
I didn't get your email.
我没有收到你的邮件
I'm sorry. I forget it.
不好意思 我忘了
I'll do it right away.
马上发你
And
还有就是
if you don't mind me asking,
我可以问一下
how can you acquire
你这些新用户的
the user information
用户资料
of the new users?
获取的渠道是
Ms. Xu,
许总监
that's a commercial secret
商业机密
that must remain confidential.
无可奉告
You're at the top.
你是领导
As long as the results are good,
结果好不就行了
leave the hard work to us.
困难的工作交给我们来
You can just
你呢就
focus on your baby.
安心养胎
Take it easy.
多休息
Blue Ocean is one of the earliest
蓝海是春江市比较早
media companies in Chunjiang,
市场份额最大的
with the largest share of the market.
新媒体公司
The founder, Yu Hai,
创始人于海呢
is a pretty famous
也是当地比较有名的
local media specialist.
新媒体人
He used to work
他曾经在传统媒体
in traditional media advertising,
负责广告业务
has incredible
具有极强的
revenue capacity and industry resources.
营收能力和业界资源
Professionally speaking,
在专业方面
he is a very capable and experienced
他是很有能力的
leader of new media, as well as the
新媒体老总
actual controller of Blue Ocean.
也是蓝海的实际掌控人
Now,
那下面
let's welcome Mr. Yu to give
我们请于总介绍一下
an introduction of the company.
公司的情况吧
Okay, Wendy.
好的 温蒂总
Don't bend over.
你别弯腰啊
What are you looking for? I'll get it.
你找什么 我来帮你找
I want to see
想找一下
the industry report of the last year.
去年的行业报告
It should be
应该就在
in one of these two boxes.
这两个箱子里边
I've rummaged this one. It's not there.
这个我翻过了 没有
It should be in a plastic folder.
应该是个塑料皮
That's it.
就这个
This one.
这个
How did you get them down?
这么重的箱子
They are so heavy.
你怎么搬下来的
Are you in such a hurry?
有那么着急吗
You can't wait for me to do it?
就不能等我两分钟啊
Blue Ocean also has made a big increase
蓝海上半年的这个流量
in user statistics earlier this year.
也猛增了一段啊
It seems like Huang Sisi
看来黄思思
is confident to make her promises,
是有成功案例
because she's made it before.
才敢打这种包票的
So that means
这么说
she is really capable.
她真有两把刷子啊
Do you know
那她用的什么招
how she does it?
你搞明白了吗
No.
没有
An increase in the statistics
这个项目
is expected due to the project.
流量会上涨 很正常
But now,
但是现在
to such an extent,
涨到这种程度
this is way beyond my expectation.
完全超出我的预判了
If she's really that good,
她要是真有能耐
Blue Ocean would never let her go.
蓝海也不能放她呀
She had other reasons
她离开蓝海
leaving Blue Ocean.
还是有别的原因的
The biggest question I have
主要让我纳闷的是
is that if she's so capable
她要真这么有能力
to maintain so many users,
能一直拉住流量的话
In the past several years, Blue Ocean
蓝海这两年的日子
should've been much better than us.
应该比我们好过不少呢
That's definitely not true.
那可真没看出来
I heard
我听说
Mr. Yu of Blue Ocean
蓝海于总
is diluting his equity,
都稀释自己股权了
raising funds everywhere.
到处在融资呢
That's a good point.
你提醒我了
I should give Yu Hai a call.
给于海打个电话
Hello, Mr. Yu,
喂 于总啊
are you available now?
方便吗
[Ms. Xu,]
老班长
I'm waiting on a call.
我这儿等一电话
Go ahead and make it short.
你长话短说啊 你说
I'm reading
我 我在看那个
the industry report.
行业报告呢
Blue Ocean
那个蓝海
had a big increase in users
上半年有段时间
in first half of the year.
流量猛增啊
I just want to ask
我就想问问
about the quality
你这些新用户
of the new users.
质量怎么样啊
Were they active users?
活跃度如何啊
Half a year ago?
半年前
Did Huang Sisi
是不是黄思思
join your company
到你们那儿之后
and made some great numbers?
来了个新官上任三把火
The secrets to boost online traffic?
弄了个流量密码的事啊
Is there anything
有没有什么消息
you can disclose to me,
可以透露一下呀
my old friend?
老同学
Ms. Xu,
我说老班长
don't pull that with me.
你这有点没意思啊
When you need something from me,
你说你求得着我的时候
it's old friends
就一口一个
and good friends all over the time.
亲同学亲同学的
But when you don't,
不求我的时候吧
I'm just Mr. Yu.
就于老板于老板的
Then what do you
那你想让我
want me to call you?
怎么称呼你啊
[Come on,]
你赶紧的
[give me something.]
跟我说说行不行
I can't.
不行
This is a commercial secret.
这可是商业机密
Commercial secret?
你还商业机密呢
Then tell me,
那你跟我说
her way to do this,
你们使这招
did it come from you
到底是你教黄思思的
or Huang Sisi?
还是黄思思教你的呀
From her?
她教我
What she knows,
她那套路啊
she learned everything
那都是在蓝海这儿
from Blue Ocean.
才学的
There's no need for me to tell you.
不是 我不跟你说
You'll know soon yourself.
你很快你也会知道
Just tell me then.
那你就跟我说说呗
No, it's that I'm afraid
不 我这不是怕
that it'll affect
影响我在你心目中
the image you have of me.
这光辉形象吗
What image
你在我心目中
do you think you have?
还有什么形象呀
What's that tone?
怎么说话呢
Do you want to know
你到底想知道
or not?
还是不想知道啊
[But I'm afraid]
但是我啊
[that someone like you,]
我怕像你这种
[with such a]
对社会
[sense of responsibility for the society,]
这么有责任感的这个
with sense of justice,
正义的这个这个
as a media person,
媒体人
wouldn't accept
你会不接受这个
this secret to boost online traffic.
流量密码
What do you mean?
什么意思啊
Putting me on a pedestal?
给我戴高帽子是吗
Cut the nonsense
别跟我废话了
and tell me.
赶紧说说
My call is coming in.
我等的电话进来了
That's it for now.
先这么着啊
Hello?
喂 喂
What?
怎么了
He hung up on me.
给我挂了
He didn't tell you?
他没说啊
It seems to be
看来这是个
a secret that can't be spoken of.
不能说的秘密呢
It's looks great on you.
好看 好看
Mrs. Jia, I can't take this.
阿姨 这个真的不能要
Keep it, you have to.
要要要 一定要收下
Shanshan,
珊珊
ever since we hired you,
自从你来了以后啊
our house became so clean and neat.
我们家就变得井井有条
I have to thank you.
我真的要好好谢谢你呀
It looks great.
真好看
Mrs. Jia,
阿姨
making you satisfied
让您满意
is my job.
这是我的本职工作
This kerchief is too big a gift.
这丝巾太贵重了
I really can't accept it, Mrs. Jia.
我真的不能收 阿姨
You must keep it.
必须要收下
Shanshan, look,
珊珊 再说了
at my age,
你说我这么大年纪了
this color
我戴这个颜色
is too light on me.
那是 太嫩了
I can't wear it.
不行 不行
It's perfect on you.
你戴正合适
It really looks great.
真的好看
Am I right, Ying?
小英 你说是吧
Yeah.
就是
This color
这个颜色
really suits your skin tone.
很衬你的皮肤啊
It looks great.
挺好看的
Keep it.
阿姨送你就收下嘛
It's great. Keep it.
好看好看 收下收下
Mrs. Jia, you're very nice.
阿姨 您太客气了
I'm not. It really looks great.
不客气 真的挺好看的
This is to thank you.
辛苦你 辛苦你
Look at you.
你看看这
Mrs. Jia.
阿姨
It looks great.
好漂亮啊
Yeah.
对啊
It really looks great.
真的是 好看 好看
Really?
是吗 好看吗
Yeah.
真的
Even the baby thinks so.
连宝宝都说好看
It looks great.
好漂亮
[It's yours.]
送给你了
[Keep it.]
收下 收下
[Mrs. Jia, you're too nice.]
阿姨 您太客气